Tim Pierce

Software Engineer (406) 781-5116 timothy.samuel.pierce@gmail.com

Summary

A software engineer with a media background and a penchant for storytelling. Known for implementing creative solutions to solve difficult problems. Specialize in synthesizing complex ideas into terms easily understood by the general public, whether it's a legislative session or a UX layout.

Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Shopify Liquid

Databases: SQL, MongoDB, MongoAtlas

Technologies: Express, JSON, EJS, Axios, Supertest, Node.js, Mongoose, Sequelize, Next.JS, React,

Django, pygame, Mocha, Chai, Bcrypt, Passport, JWT, Bulma, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Selenium

Software and Resources: GitHub, VSCode, Postman, Photoshop, Audition, Premiere, Illustrator

Software Engineer Experience

Freelance Engineer | Self | August 2023 - Present

- Working with several organizations to optimize their sites, such as KLOS Guitars, or building brand new sites for private entities
- Maintain clear and frequent communication with clients to achieve their vision in a timely manner
- Able to create style choices to align with the company's branding with little direction from the company
- Rebuilding an eCommerce company's website (<u>www.klosguitars.com</u>) using Shopify Liquid, HTML and CSS

Software Engineer Fellow | General Assembly | Feb 2023 - August 2023

- 24-week intensive software engineering program
- Received a comprehensive understanding of languages such as HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and Python
- Built 4 projects that reflect skill sets in SQL and NoSQL databases, as well as Node.JS and frequently used dependencies

Software Engineer Projects

sirteT | Browser game with HTML5/CSS/JS

- Utilized a JavaScript canvas to make a reserve-Tetris where the goal is to fill the screen with as many blocks as possible
- Used advanced array logic to create an array table that serves as the gameboard. The game loop draws the board every frame, including the falling pieces, and checks whether or not the falling piece intersects with placed pieces
- Created win and lose states that trigger when the pieces go over the top of the game board.

Civvi | Full Stack App with JS, SQL and Sequelize

- Created an app that pulls from Congress's API using Axios and populates a SQL database
- Implemented routes using Express and Sequelize that allow users to parse through congressional legislative committees
- Used bcrypt and JWT tokens to authenticate users, as well as salt and hash their passwords for added security
- Incorporated the supertest dependency to test routes under several edge-case scenarios

Tim Pierce

Software Engineer

(406) 781-5116

timothy.samuel.pierce@gmail.com

ELIXIR | Full Stack App with React, MongoDB and Mongoose

- Collaboratively developed a MERN stack app with three other developers that pulls from the CocktailDB to populate a social media site centered around creating and sharing cocktail recipes
- Incorporated several CSS tricks to make the app more interactive and visually engaging, such as enlarging tiles that users hover over or adding ingredient descriptions when users hover over an ingredient
- Built complex React components, such as a dynamic search bar that populates return data based on the user's input

Tim-agotchi | Full Stack App with React, MongoDB and Mongoose

- Developed an engaging Tamagotchi-inspired web application using the Next.js framework, enabling users to raise and nurture virtual animals.
- Implemented dynamic and responsive user interfaces using React components, ensuring an intuitive and visually appealing experience for users interacting with their virtual pets.
- Utilized MongoDB to store and manage the state and attributes of virtual animals, such as hunger, happiness, and health, enabling users to monitor and care for their digital companions.
- Integrated user authentication and session management to allow multiple users to create and interact with their personalized virtual pets within the web app.

Professional Experience

Public Relations Director | KLOS Guitars | September 2021 - Present

- Planned and executed targeted media campaigns for a small start-up, including email marketing campaigns that increased company y-to-d profits by over 20 percent
- Organized and executed PR campaigns to bolster the public perception of the brand, which led to KLOS adoption in over 100 retail stores across the United States
- Rebranded the company website to establish a premium look and feel to the products

Producer, News Host | KCPW, Salt Lake Public Radio | June 2019 - August 2021

- Crafted half-hour radio programs from inception to broadcast entirely by myself which led to me winning several industry awards, including SPJ "Best Radio Feature"
- Enhanced voice-over content through meticulous copyediting, resulting in optimized SEO performance and increased online visibility
- Delivered daily live local news broadcasts, engaging a wide audience and achieving consistent viewership metrics.

Reporter | Montana Legislative News Service | August 2018-May 2019

- Created daily audio and print reports covering the Montana Legislature for various state-wide news organizations, including MTPR and the Missoulian
- Covered the 2018 Montana midterm elections, including fact-checking debates and producing congressional candidate profiles for an audience of nearly 400,000 people
- Operated under a strict daily deadline and was able to quickly adapt to complex, breaking news
- Synthesized complex topics, such as the debate against Medicaid expansion into small, digestible content so that the average reader or listener could understand what exactly their representatives were doing in the legislature

Education

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive | Sep 2023 University of Montana | School of Journalism | Specialized in audio and social media | May 2019